<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Github Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://shocm.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shocm.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-30T13:40:13-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://shocm.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[shocm]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[eric@esolves.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Caching: A Brief Overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://shocm.github.io/blog/2013/05/30/caching-a-brief-overview/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T13:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://shocm.github.io/blog/2013/05/30/caching-a-brief-overview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another <a href="http://www.sdphp.org/2013/05/meetup-13-caching-a-brief-overview/">SDPHP MeetUp</a> last night and another good talk. Aaron Scherer (<a href="https://twitter.com/aequasi">@aequasi</a>) did a great job discussing different types of Cache solutions such as OpCode Caches (APC, Zend Optimizer, eAccelerator, XCache, and HipHop) and Data Caches (APC, Memcached, and Redis). Worth a click through</p>

<p style="text-align: center;">
<iframe style="border: 1px solid #CCC; border-width: 1px 1px 0; margin-bottom: 5px;" src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/22206852" height="356" width="427" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><strong> <a title="Caching" href="http://www.slideshare.net/aequasi/caching-22206852" target="_blank">Caching</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/aequasi" target="_blank">Aaron Scherer</a></strong></div>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Encryption: It's For More Than Just Password]]></title>
    <link href="http://shocm.github.io/blog/2013/05/27/encryption-its-for-more-than-just-password/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-27T21:39:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://shocm.github.io/blog/2013/05/27/encryption-its-for-more-than-just-password</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year at <a href="http://tek.phparch.com/">tek13</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/johncongdon">John Congdon</a> gave this talk about PHP and Encryption. I didn&rsquo;t get a chance to attend the conference this year but I did get to see a preview of the talk a couple of times as <a href="https://twitter.com/johncongdon">John</a> practiced his presentation on the <a href="http://www.sdphp.org/">SDPHP</a> group. It&rsquo;s very informative and has me really looking forward to a couple new features that should be released in the next version of <a href="http://www.php.net/manual/en/migration55.new-features.php">PHP version 5.5.</a></p>

<p style="text-align: center;">
<iframe style="border: 1px solid #CCC; border-width: 1px 1px 0; margin-bottom: 5px;" src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/21222515" height="356" width="427" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><strong> <a title="Encryption: It's For More Than Just Password - tek13" href="http://www.slideshare.net/johncongdon/encryption-its-for-more-than-just-password-tek13" target="_blank">Encryption: It&#8217;s For More Than Just Password - tek13</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/johncongdon" target="_blank">John Congdon</a></strong></div>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2 Weeks as a Programmer]]></title>
    <link href="http://shocm.github.io/blog/2013/05/13/2-weeks-as-a-programmer/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-13T07:46:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://shocm.github.io/blog/2013/05/13/2-weeks-as-a-programmer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://www.shocm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screenshot_5_13_13_5_46_PM-3.png" width="150" height="150" title="Coding" ></p>

<p>I am starting the 3rd week of my journey, you see I am a “seasoned” IT guy. I’ve been working in the IT industry professionally, in some form or fashion, for a number of years. I’ve been tinkering with computers longer than that. My first computer was a TRS80-CoCo2 I got for Christmas, I want to say back in 1984.</p>

<p>The first thing I did was teach myself BASIC. I would spend hours coding small applications that really didn’t do much of anything. I also started to tinker around with how the computer worked, how did it communicate with my dot-matrix printer, or the joy stick. This opened up my vision of the field of computers a lot.</p>

<p>As an adult I found myself in the IT field. This really wasn’t that surprising. I had found myself on the track of an Operations guy. You may ask yourself “What is a ‘Operations Guy’?”, basically anything short of programming or one of the specialized fields like security, databases, etc. Ops is the heart of everything, making the systems talk to each other and typically the guys who work the odd hours, weekends and holiday to make changes and not impact day-to-day production. We are talking networking, hardware, backups, managing, monitoring, patching, so on and so on.</p>

<p>This is a great field to build a career on, my only problem was I love programming. I mean its one of the things I am passionate about. For years I was a hobby developer, building small applications here and there on the side. I was also fortunate in the sense I always seem to manage to have small development task at work. The longer I worked in the IT field the more I wanted to focus on development.</p>

<p>A few years back the phrase “DevOps” was really gaining popularity and I tried to position myself more and more into a DevOps role. At the time I was working for a Fortune 100 company. Very corporate in its ways of thinking and very slow-moving. They pretty much had the opposite philosophy, leaning more to people becoming very specialized in a specific field or task. About a year ago I decided to make a change and took on a role with a much smaller company in hopes to develop more of the DevOps role. At first it was very promising but eventually it also turned into a typically Operations role.</p>

<p>All this time I continued to better my development skills. Learning as much as I could from languages to best practices. I got more and more involved with the development community and developed some fantastic connections and friendships. When I expressed how unsatisfied I was with the direction my job was taking it was through their encouragement I decided to take somewhat of a leap and look for a position that was more focused on development.</p>

<p>Today I start my 3rd week as a developer. I will chronicle this adventure here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
